Wenqi Wang

E-mail: wang2041@purdue.edu
Mail: 514 N. 7th Street, Apt 3, Lafayette, IN, 47901
Tel: +1(765)418-4386
Web: http://web.ics.purdue.edu/~wang2041/

Research Interest

My primary research interests include Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Tensor Networks. Currently, I am working on tensor networks, and its application in dimensionality reduction and missing data completion for multi-dimensional data, and model compression and acceleration for deep neural networks.

Education

Purdue University, School of Industrial Engineering
Ph.D. in Operation Research (GPA: 3.98/4.0)
Thesis: Multi-dimensional data analytics and deep learning via tensor networks.
Minor in Computational Science and Engineering (CS&E) Program

Fudan University, Department of Physics
B.S. in Physics
Sep, 2009 – July, 2013
UC Berkeley Extension Concurrent Enrollment Program

West Lafayette, IN, U.S.
Aug, 2013 – Aug, 2018

Shanghai, China
Sep, 2009 – July, 2013

Aug, 2012 – Dec, 2012

Experience

Technicolor Research AI Lab

Los Altos, CA, U.S.

Research Internship in Optimization Techniques for Deep Learning

Jun, 2017 - Sep, 2017

- Mentors: Yifan Sun and Brian Eriksson
- Proposed a Tensor Ring Networks to compress the state-of-the-arts neural networks (CVPR2018).
- Proposed a new efficient Tucker Ring factorization to analyze multi-dimensional data.

FREEs Fund
Beijing, China

Investment Analyst Internship

Dec, 2016 - Jan, 2017

- Mentors: Xiang Gao
 - Assisted investment managers to conduct industrial analysis in big data and artificial intellegence.

School of Industrial Engineering, Purdue University

West Lafayette, IN

Teaching Assistant for Stochastic Process

Aug, 2015 – May. 2017

• Prepared course contents and exercise problems in Discrete Time Markov Chain, Continuous Time Markov Chain, Queuing Theory, and Brownian Motion.

Publication

- [1] Wenqi Wang, Brian Eriksson, Yifan Sun, Wenlin Wang, Vaneet Aggarwal, Wide-compression: Tensor Ring Nets. IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR 2018)
- [2] Wenlin Wang, Zhe Gan, **Wenqi Wang**, Dinghan Shen, Jiaji Huang, Wei Ping, Sanjeev Satheesh, Lawrence Carin, Topic Compositional Neural Language Model. Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (**AISTATS 2018**)
- [3] Wenqi Wang, Vaneet Aggarwal, Shuchin Aeron, Tensor Train Neighborhood Preserving Embedding. IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing (TSP 2018)
- [4] Wenqi Wang, Vaneet Aggarwal, Shuchin Aeron, Efficient Low Rank Tensor Ring Completion. IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV 2017)
- [5] Wenqi Wang, Vaneet Aggarwal, Shuchin Aeron, Principal Component Analysis with Tensor Train Subspace (arXiv:1803.05026)
- [6] Wenqi Wang, Vaneet Aggarwal, Shuchin Aeron, Tensor Completion by Alternative Minimization under Tensor Train (TT) Model (arXiv:1609.05587)
- [7] Wenlin Wang, Changyou Chen, **Wenqi Wang**, Piyush Rai, Lawrence Carin, Earliness-Aware Deep Convolutional Networks for Early Time Series Classification (arXiv:1611.04578)
- [8] Wenqi Wang, Vaneet Aggarwal, Shuchin Aeron, Unsupervised Clustering Under the Union of Polyhedral Cones (UOPC) Model. Pattern Recognition Letters (PRL 2017)
- [9] Wenqi Wang, Vaneet Aggarwal, Shuchin Aeron, On Deterministic Conditions for Subspace Clustering Under Missing Data. IEEE International Symposium on Information Theory (ISIT 2016)

- [10] Yaowu Hu, Seunghyun Lee, Prashant Kumar, Qiong Nian, **Wenqi Wang**, Joseph Irudayaraj and Gary J. Cheng. Water flattens graphene wrinkles:laser shock wrapping of graphene onto substrate-supported crystalline plasmonic nanoparticle arrays (**Nanoscale**. 2015)
- [11] Dong Lin, Qiong Nian, Biwei Deng, Shengyu Jin, Yaowu Hu, Wenqi Wang, and Gary J. Cheng. Three-Dimensional Printing of Complex Structures: Man Made or toward Nature? (ACS Nano, 2014)
- [12] Y. L. Chen, Y. J. Ma, D. D. Chen, W. Q. Wang, K. Ding, Q. Wu, Y. L. Fan, X. J. Yang, Z. Y. Zhong, F. Xu, and Z. M. Jiang. Effect of graphene on photoluminescence properties of graphene/GeSi quantum dot hybrid structures. (Appl. Phys. Lett. 2014)

Presentation

- [1] Multi-dimensional data analytics and deep learning via tensor networks. Yahoo, New York, NY, USA Apr. 2018
- [2] Multi-dimensional data analytics and deep learning via tensor networks. Computational Interdisciplinary Graduate Programs (CIGP) Symposium, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN, USA Apr. 2018
- [3] Tensor Train Subspace Embedding, SIAM Computational Science and Engineering Student Conference (CSESC), Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN, USA

 Mar. 2017
- [4] National Investment Banking Competition (NIBC) Final Round Presentation, Vancouver, BC, Canada, Feb. 2016

Awards

Bilsland Dissertation Fellowship, Purdue University 20	017-2018
Purdue Krannert Finance Club Travel Awards, Purdue University Ma	ar. 2016
Honored Graduation Awards, Fudan University July 2015 Awards Student University	ıl. 2013
National Mount Everest Program Fellowship, Fudan University Se	p. 2012
TOSHIBA Scholarship, Fudan University 20	12-2013
People's Scholarship 2nd Prize, Fudan University	009-2012

Skills

Technical expertise: Python(Tensorflow), C/C++, Matlab, Emacs, Linux.

Certificate: Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) Level 1, Financial Risk Manager (FRM) Level 1.

Languages: Mandarin (mother tongue), English (professional proficiency).

Related Course

Mathematics: Mathematics Finance I, Mathematics Finance II, Stochastic Process, Theoretical Foundation in Optimization, Mathematics of Data Science, Introduction to Probability, Linear Programming, Numerical Analysis

Machine Learning: Artificial Intelligence, Pattern Recognition, Bioinformatics Algorithms

Economics and Finance: Microeconomics, Macroeconomics, Monetary Banking, Corporate Finance

Reference

Vaneet Aggarwal (E-mail: vaneet@purdue.edu; Tel: +1(765)496-0398)

- · Assistant Professor, School of Industrial Engineering, Purdue University
- Prof.Aggarwal is my graduate advisor at Purdue University.

Shuchin Aeron (E-mail: shuchin@ece.tufts.edu; Tel: +1(617)627-4653)

- Associate Professor, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Tufts University
- Prof.Aeron is my research collaborator.

Yifan Sun (E-mail: yifan.sun@technicolor.com)

- Researcher, Technicolor Research AI Lab
- Dr.Sun is my mentor during my internship at Technicolor Research.

Brian Eriksson (E-mail: eriksson@adobe.com; Tel: +1(612)860-7915)

- Area Lead, Technicolor Research AI Lab
- Dr.Eriksson is my mentor during my internship at Technicolor Research.